[型一與型二錯誤率]
One of the three approaches drawn
inferences from your data was the path of
前面提到三種從資料進行推論的法門。第一種是
付諸行動，正式名稱「尼曼-皮爾生方法」
Action, the Limon Pearson approach.
前面提到三種從資料進行推論的法門。第一種是
付諸行動，正式名稱「尼曼-皮爾生方法」
In the Nymen Pearson approach, the main
thing is trying to control the errors
尼曼-皮爾生方法的要訣是控制(每一次)
推論資料會犯下的錯誤
when you draw inferences from your data.
尼曼-皮爾生方法的要訣是控制(每一次)
推論資料會犯下的錯誤
When you say yes,
I accept the null hypothesis or
當你說「我接受虛無假設」
I will reject the null hypothesis,
或者說「我拒絕虛無假設」
controlling the amount of times in
the long run that you make a mistake.
都是為了控制多次實驗結論犯錯的次數
Now we talk about this in
terms of the Type 1 and
先來談談你會犯的型一與型二錯誤
是什麼意思
the Type 2 Errors that you can make.
先來談談你會犯的型一與型二錯誤
是什麼意思
In the goal of error control,
what you try to do is prevent
為了控制犯錯率，首先要避免在多次實驗裡
犯下太多愚弄自已的錯誤
making a fool out of yourself,
too often, in the long run and
為了控制犯錯率，首先要避免在多次實驗裡
犯下太多愚弄自已的錯誤
I think this is a very useful thing to try
when you draw inferences from your data.
避免這種錯誤經常能讓你從資料做出有效推論
Now let's take a look at an example.
現在，讓我們看這一個例子
Let's say you're walking down the street
and you come across this person.
假想你是(吸血鬼殺手)，在路上巧遇這名男子
And you have some suspicions that
this person might be a vampire, but
他的外表讓你懷疑他是吸血鬼還是
從不出門曬太陽的宅男
it could also be someone who's
not getting enough sunlight.
他的外表讓你懷疑他是吸血鬼還是
從不出門曬太陽的宅男
You have to make a decision to either
stake or not stake this individual.
你的任務是決定要不要拿起尖木棍插入他的心臟
And this person can be a true vampire or
這名男子也許真的是個吸血鬼
it can just be a random
person on the street.
也許只是剛好出門的宅男
So we see that there's
a possibility that you
劇情接下來可能會如此發展
correctly identify this person
as a vampire and stake them.
你看穿他是真的吸血鬼，並且刺死他
But you can also make an error.
不過也有可能是錯殺或錯放的劇情
You can make two types of error.
也就是型一錯誤與型二錯誤
Type one error is, well this is a vampire
when actually it's not a vampire.
錯殺的劇情(型一錯誤)：你以為他是吸血鬼
但其實不是
And in this case you would
stake an innocent person.
在這個劇情裡，你殺了無辜的宅男
(台灣本土劇會演你被家屬追殺)
The second type of error that you
can make, the type two error is
錯放的劇情(型二錯誤)：你沒看穿
他是真正的吸血鬼
saying that this is probably not
a vampire when it actually is a vampire.
錯放的劇情(型二錯誤)：你沒看穿
他是真正的吸血鬼
And in this case,
you probably going to end up dead,
這樣的劇情大概會走向你被吸血鬼
吸光全身血液而死的結局
because this vampire is going to
suck all the blood out of you.
這樣的劇情大概會走向你被吸血鬼
吸光全身血液而死的結局
Let's take a look at some definitions
when we're talking about this topic.
接著定義一些待會討論會提到的名詞
So first,
we have to define the null hypothesis and
首先定義「虛無假設」與「對立假設」
通常簡稱H0與H1
the alternative hypothesis,
which we'll often indicate with H0 and H1.
首先定義「虛無假設」與「對立假設」
通常簡稱H0與H1
It's important to keep in
請記住這個重點
mind that the null hypothesis doesn't
necessarily need to be the prediction that
虛無假設並不一定得是預測
數種實驗情況的差異剛好為零
the difference between certain
conditions is exactly zero.
虛無假設並不一定得是預測
數種實驗情況的差異剛好為零
Think about flipping a coin, in which
case the null hypothesis is probably that
記得前一講提到的擲硬幣例子
例子裡的虛無假設大概就是
there's a 50% probability of
flipping heads and tails.
有50%機率的擲出正面朝上或反面朝上
So the null hypothesis can be anything.
虛無假設可以是指任何可能結果
But very often,
只是大多數情況下
it's the idea that there's no difference
between two experimental conditions.
剛好是指兩組實驗情境的結果無顯著差異
The alpha that we use as
the probability of a significant result
alpha是指我們能夠接受的「拒絕虛無假設，
when the null hypothesis is true.
但虛無假設實際為真」的犯錯機率
And this is the definition
of a type 1 error rate.
這也是型一錯誤的定義
And you're free to set this alpha
at any level that you want.
你可以將 alpha定在任何你想要的水準
A very often used level in psychology is
5% but we already saw that in some fields
心理學領域常見的alpha是5%,
但是不同領域習慣的水準並不相同
like physics it's very common to set
in much much lower type one error rate.
前一講提到的物理學
預訂的型一錯誤率就非常低
And you can also think about areas such as
medicine where it might be useful to set
其它講究嚴謹的科學領域，像是醫學
也習慣把 alpha訂得非常低
a much lower error rate as well.
其它講究嚴謹的科學領域，像是醫學
也習慣把 alpha訂得非常低
The beta is the probability
of a non-significant result,
beta 指的是犯下「接受虛無假設，但對立假設
實際為真」的機率
given that the alternative
hypothesis is true.
beta 指的是犯下「接受虛無假設，但對立假設
實際為真」的機率
This is known as a type 2 error.
也就是型二錯誤
So this is the probability that you'll
say, there is nothing going on here.
型二錯誤率代表你宣稱沒有任何實驗效果
When there's actually true
effects to be observed.
但是實驗效果並未被觀察到的狀況
If we look at the difference of 1-B,
this is
和 (1-Beta)做個比較就知道
the probability of the significant result
when the alternative hypothesis is true.
1-Beta是顯示有統計顯著，
而且對立假設為真的機率
So this is the statistical power.
因此1-Beta也被稱為統計考驗力(power)
When you design a study, one minus
the type two error rate is the probability
設計研究時計算統計考驗力
可以用來估計
that you'll actually find the result
if there is a true effect to be found.
顯著結果是因為確實發現實際效果的機率
Now remember that Naiman thinks that these
error rates are frequentist concepts,
尼曼談論這些錯誤率是根據「次數分配」
so they apply to the long run.
也就是累積多次重覆實驗結果來看
Now in any single study there's
either a true effect or not.
單獨的研究結果，可能會也可能不會
發現真實效果
You were right or you were wrong.
所以一次結果的推論有可能對，也有可能錯
But these error rates are about
long-run frequencies.
但是錯誤率皆是得自持續重覆實驗結果
推論錯誤次數的累積
So you can be 5% of the time,
you can make a mistake.
你可以宣稱這一次的推論
有平均5%的機率是錯誤的
But in any single study,
you've either made a mistake or not.
對於單一研究結果的推論
有可能對也有可能錯
It's important to think
about this in the long run.
但是請永遠記得這一次的對錯
只是多次重覆實驗的其中一次
So if you do many, many studies, how often
will you make an incorrect conclusion?
那麼你要如何計算在多次實驗梩
做出錯誤推論的次數有多少？
Because we have these two situations
where the null hypothesis is true or
我們面對兩種可能狀況，推論虛無假設為真
the alternative hypothesis is true,
或者推論對立假設為真(上兩欄)
and you can either observe a significant
effect or you will find a non-significant
還有觀察結果可能是顯著的
或者不顯著的(左兩欄)
result, we can divide these
options into these four cells.
這些情況構成四種可能後果
(細格之內)
And here we can see that when
the null hypothesis is true and
左上細格就是虛無假設確實為真
you find a significant effect,
you've made a false positive.
但發現顯著效果，就犯下假警報的錯誤
(偽陽性 false positive)
A type I error.
或者說「型一錯誤」
You said there is something here
when there are actually nothing.
表示結論說有效果，但實際是沒有效果
When the null hypothesis true you can also
correctly say that there is no true effect
左下細格是虛無假設為真，結論宣稱沒有效果
which we called a true negative.
這種後果是正確拒絕
(true negative 真陰性)
Now in the alternative hypothesis is true.
再看到右上細格，對立假設為真的情況
You find this significance effect,
that's a true positive.
這是發現顯著效果，而且結論命中的後果
(真陽性 true positive)
Something is going on and
you correctly identified it.
也就是宣稱有效果，
並且真正有效果存在
You can also draw the conclusion
that there is nothing going on,
最後右下角是結論沒有效果
when there is actually a true effect.
但是效果的確存在的「未命中」
And we call this a false negative.
這種後果就是錯誤否定
(偽陰性 false nagative)
Now remember that in any single case
you're either sampling from a true effect
稍早已說明一次實驗結果可能是真實效果
or from a false effect.
或著是錯誤地發現效果
So you're in one of two parallel worlds.
虛無與對立假設好比兩個平行世界
Either there is no true effect And
then you can only make false positives or
要麼你在虛無假設的世界，在「假警報」
與「正確否定」兩種推論擇一
true negatives.
要麼你在虛無假設的世界，在「假警報」
與「正確否定」兩種推論擇一
Or you're doing research where there is
actually a true effect and then you can
不然就是研究確實發現效果，在「命中」
與「未命中」兩種推論擇一
only make a correct conclusion
a true positive or a false negative.
不然就是研究確實發現效果，在「命中」
與「未命中」兩種推論擇一
Now let's take this understanding of
type one errors and type two errors and
接著運用這張表格列出的型一與型二錯誤，
命中與正確否定等概念
true positives and
接著運用這張表格列出的型一與型二錯誤，
命中與正確否定等概念
true negatives to think about what's most
likely to happen in your next study.
評估進行一項新研究的結果會遇到什麼後果
(以下內容建議完成練習測驗再來看一次)
I'll describe a typical situation
which I think is fair and
在一個典型的研究裡，
虛無與對立假設成真的機率相等
describes many of the studies that we do.
與我們會做的研究大部份相同
Let say, that you don't really know
if there's a true effect or not.
也就是說我們並不知道是否
真的發現真實效果
The null hypothesis might be true, the
alternative hypothesis might be true and
虛無假設可能為真
對立假設也可能為真
both are equally likely.
而且兩者為真的機率是相同的
Let's give them both 50%, we just
don't know what's going to happened.
所以兩者為真的機率各設定50%
代表不知道會發現那一種結果
We also use a type one error rate,
同時也像大多數研究一樣
設定型一錯誤率為5%
the alpha of 5% which is very
同時也像大多數研究一樣
設定型一錯誤率為5%
And we'll aim for
statistical power of 80%.
我們希望統計考驗力有 80%
Which means that there is
a type two error rate of 20%.
也就是說型二錯誤率為 20%
If there is a true effect,
we will not observe it in 20% on the time.
代表如果真有效果，
有20%的機會不會發現顯著結果
That's sounds like a lot maybe, but
80%聽起來很高
this is actually a very
recommended power to aim for.
然而這是一致推薦要達到的統計考驗力標準
So in this specific situation,
在如此設定的條件下
let's assume that this
reflects what you want to do.
假設這就是你要完成的研究
You use this type 1 error rate.
你設定這樣的型一錯誤率
And you actually exactly
meet this statistical power.
且決定追求這樣的統計考驗力標準
You have 80% power in your next study.
你的新研究結果要根據80%的考驗力推論
You never really know but
let's assume that this is the case.
雖然你無法確定有達到，
先姑且如此設定
Think a moment what's
the most likely to happen.
資料分析完成的那一刻會發生什麼事？
Will you find a significant result or
a non-significant result?
你會看到顯著的，還是不顯著的結果?
Make a false positive or a false negative?
結論是假警報還是未命中?
And let's do the math and
see what really happens.
讓我們計算一下各種可能結果的機率
(完成練習測驗再來看更能理解)
So as we said, there's a 50% probability
that a no-hypothesis is true and
在上方兩欄，
標記虛無假設為真的機率為50%
a 50% probability that
the alternative hypothesis is true.
以及標記對立假設為真的機率為50%
Remember, we just didn't know
what was going to happen.
再次提醒，這表示不曉得何者為真
We have a 5% type 1 error rate and
a 20% type 2 error rate.
左側兩欄標記型一錯誤率5%
與型二錯誤率20%
So, we can use these numbers to
calculate the probability of
如此就能計算四種結果發生的機率
each of these four cells to happen, and
of course, they should add up to 100%.
並且四者的總和必為100%
(建議停格親自算一下)
Let's first assume that
the alternative hypothesis is true,
先來看對立假設為真的這邊
we're examining a true effect.
這邊代表推論存在真實效果
The probability of finding a significant
effect equals the statistical power that
發現顯著效果的機率等於統計考驗力(80%)
乘以對立假設為真的機率(50%)
we have, which is 80% and its 50% probable
that the alternative hypothesis is true.
發現顯著效果的機率等於統計考驗力(80%)
乘以對立假設為真的機率(50%)
So we can multiply 80% by 50% and
所以 80% 乘以 50%就等於40%
代表結論有效果為正確的機率
we find that it's 40% likely that we
conclude that there's a true effect.
所以 80% 乘以 50%就等於40%
代表結論有效果為正確的機率
A true positive.
也有人稱為真陽率
(true positive)
It's also possible that we find
a non significant effect this will
右下細格是發現不顯著的結果
happen 20% of the time.
有20%的機率發生
Multiplying 20% with the 50% probability
of the alternative hypothesis being true
所以將20%乘以50%的對立假設為真的機率
gives us a 10% probability
of making a false negative.
就會得到10%推論未命中的機率
(偽陰率)
Now let's move over to the situation
where the null hypothesis is true.
現在把目光移到虛無假設為真的這一欄
Here we have a 5% error rate.
統計顯著的結果有5%的犯錯率
We can multiply this 5% times the 50%
probability of the no hypothesis
將5%乘以50%的虛無假設為真的機率，
is true and in 2.5% of the time we'll
conclude that there's a false positive.
得到做出結論為假警報的機率是2.5
(偽陽率)
We'll say that there is an effect when
there's actually no effect to be found.
也就是說，不存在真實效果
結論卻認為存在的機率
And now we come to the most likely outcome
in this very typical situation, a true.
最後左下角是這個研究最可能發生的推論結果
There's a 95% probability that will
conclude that nothing is going on.
首先有95%的機率沒有發現顯著效果
Multiply it by the 50%
probability that the null
乘以50%的虛無假設為真的機率
hypothesis is true which gives us 47.5%.
得到47.5%的機率
So that's the highest number of
these four possible outcomes.
而且是這四種結果推論最有可能發生的
And this might be surprising
if you do a new study and
你也許會很驚訝，如果一項新研究
不知虛無還是對立假設何者為真
you don't know whether the null is true or
the alternative is true,
你也許會很驚訝，如果一項新研究
不知虛無還是對立假設何者為真
you use the recommended alpha level and
the recommended statistical power.
使用建議的 alpha 值與統計考驗力標準
Then the most likely outcome of
your next study is a true negative.
最有可能的結果竟然是正確拒絕
(真陰率)
Nothing is going on and you correctly
conclude that nothing is going on.
什麼效果都沒有是最有可能正確的結論
So you might be surprised that the most
likely outcome is a true negative, and
所以你也許會驚訝，正確拒絕竟然是多次實驗
最常出現的正確結論，卻不是最令人感興趣的
very often, your interested in
finding significant effect and
所以你也許會驚訝，正確拒絕竟然是多次實驗
最常出現的正確結論，卻不是最令人感興趣的
finding support for
the alternative hypothesis.
支持對立假設的顯著結果
Saying, there is a true effect and
比方說確實有真實效果
correctly concluding that
there is a true effect.
而且已有研究支持確實存在
So how can you improve these
probabilities in the previous slides?
那麼要如何改進前一張投影片例子的四種結果
之間的相對機率
Well there are different options.
其實有不少可行方案
Let's take a look at what works best.
讓我們來看一下怎樣能得到最好的效果
You might say, the problem here is
probably that I only had 80% power.
你也許想，現在的問題是我只有80%的統計考驗力
When there is a true effect,
I only had an 80% probability
也就是有真實效果時，我只有80%的機率
of finding the effect when it's there, and
I need to increase my statistical power.
能真正發現它，所以需要增加統計考驗力
Now in this slide you can
see the red numbers and
這張投影片的紅色數字
we have increased the power to 99 percent.
就是把考驗力增加到99%
Which means that almost all of the time,
you correctly conclude
幾乎等於說，如果真實效果存在的話
你都能正確地做出結論
that there is an effect when there
is a true effect to be observed.
幾乎等於說，如果真實效果存在的話
你都能正確地做出結論
Our true positive rate
has indeed increased.
正陽率的確因此增加
(40% => 49.5%)
But not so much.
但是不明顯
(9.5%)
You can see that now
it's about 94.5% likely
你看得出，現在有49.5%的機率
(Daniel口誤)
that you conclude that
there's a true positive.
正確地推論有命中真實效果
It is now the most likely outcome but
it's not ridiculously high.
雖然是四者最有可能的結果，
比正確拒絕高不了多少
Another idea you might have is say,
另外一個你可能會想到的辦法是
well probably the false
positive rate is too high.
也許偽陽率太高了
Let's reduce the false positive rate.
那就設法降低吧
Set it at 1%.
把alpha設為1%
So Type 1 error is now 1%.
所以現在型一錯誤率為1%
And you can see where changes occur.
可以看到虛無假設為真的這欄
也就是假警報與正確拒絕的發生率有改變
Now of course the difference is only
in the situation when null hypothesis is
可以看到虛無假設為真的這欄
也就是假警報與正確拒絕的發生率有改變
actually true.
可以看到虛無假設為真的這欄
也就是假警報與正確拒絕的發生率有改變
Because you can only make a Type 1
error if the null hypothesis is true.
因為型一錯誤只與虛無假設為真有關
So we see that there's a reduction in
the number of false positives from 2.5%.
偽陽率很明顯地從2.5%降到0.5%
Now it's only 0.5%.
But still,
true negatives are most likely to happen.
然而正確拒絕依然是最可能正確的推論
So this all doesn't really help.
所以只改變型一或型二錯誤率效果不大
So whats the most important thing
to do if you want to improve
所以想要增加真陽率的話，
到底該怎麼做的呢?
the probability of
finding a true positive?
所以想要增加真陽率的話，
到底該怎麼做的呢?
What you should do is examine
hypotheses that are likely to be true.
治本之道是檢查實驗效果存在的假設
The biggest problem here is this
50/50 prior probability of the null and
真正關鍵是虛無假設與對立假設
為真的先驗機率比例(50%/50%)
the alternative hypothesis being true.
真正關鍵是虛無假設與對立假設
為真的先驗機率比例(50%/50%)
We can see that if it's above
90% probable that we are right.
如果對立假設為真的先驗機率提高到90%
That our hypothesis is 90% likely to
be true when we start data collection.
也就是蒐集資料之前，就知道對立假設為真的機率是90%
You can see that the probability of
a true positive increases sharply.
如此一來的結論命中率會大大的提高
Now, I always use these calculations
whenever a masters student
每當有碩士班學生到我辦公室
吿訴我說：「我有一個瘋狂的好點子，
enters my office and says,
I have a crazy idea.
每當有碩士班學生到我辦公室
吿訴我說：「我有一個瘋狂的好點子，
I don't know if it's true or
not, but this is my passion,
我不知能不能真的發現，
但是我願意付出時間精力
this is something that I really find
interesting and I want to examine it.
我真的很想要做這個研究。」
我總是做一次這些計算給他看。
I always say, that's perfectly fine.
我總是回答，你的點子很好
But I don't know if
the hypothesis is true or not.
但我不知道這個假設是否為真
It's 50/50.
先驗機率比是 50/50
Could go either way.
任何結果都有可能
So realize that the most likely outcome
of your research is a true negative.
你必須瞭解這個情況最有可能的正確結果就是
正確拒絕存在真實效果
If you're interested in finding.
如果你真有想法找到支持對立假設為真的證據
Support for the alternative hypothesis,
the best thing you can do is examine
如果你真有想法找到支持對立假設為真的證據
studies that are, or examined hypotheses
that are most likely to be true.
最好從己知有可能為真的假設下手
Now let's use a slightly different way
to think about these type one errors and
現在讓我們透過視覺化來看型一與型二錯誤
以及命中與正確拒絕的推論成功率
type two errors and
true positives and true negatives.
現在讓我們透過視覺化來看型一與型二錯誤
以及命中與正確拒絕的推論成功率
This is an illustration of
the null hypothesis and
虛無假設與對立假設的機率分配都設定符合常態分配
the alternative hypothesis in
terms of normal distributions.
虛無假設與對立假設的機率分配都設定符合常態分配
You can visit this website and play around
with this visualization if you want to.
你可以透過右下角連結到這個網頁自己玩玩看
Let's look at all the different components
here because there's quite a lot of
視覺化包裝許多訊息，需要花點時間看一下各種組成成份
information.
Now the white bell shaped curve Is the
situation when the null hypothesis is true.
投影片裡白色鐘型曲線是指虛無假設為真的部分
When there is no true
effect to be observed.
代表實驗結果不會觀察到真實效果的情況
You can see that it centered at zero.
你可以看到它的中央點是為0
So, this reflects the situation
where the null hypothesis is true,
所以這個分配包含虛無假設為真的所有情況
there is no true effect but,
there are some random variation.
表示沒有任何效果存在，但有一些隨機誤差
Now, if we take a look a light
blue bell shaped curve
再來看淡藍的鐘型曲線
This is the distribution when
there is a true effect and
這是代表真實效果存在的機率分配
in this case there's a true effect
of a specific size, namely 0.35.
這個範例的真實效果量是0.35
We'll talk about effect sizes
later in the course, but for
我們在後面的課程裡會再討論到效果量
now you can see that the likelihood
of finding effects that are large
不過可以看到在對立假設分配發現這個效果
的似然性是相當高的
is much more likely under
the alternative hypothesis.
不過可以看到在對立假設分配發現這個效果
的似然性是相當高的
And under the null hypothesis you'll
find effect sizes that are zero most of
在虛無假設的機率分配裡，
發現的效果量多數接近零
the time. There's a certain
critical value that we often use,
我們通常會設定一個臨界值(critical value)
it's also illustrated here, and in this
case, this equals a p value of 0.05.
在這個範例裡對應p值等於.05
So this is the critical value,
your type one error rate.
所以這個臨界值也等於型一錯誤率
Now given this cutoff
off the distributions,
從這個臨界值切下去的兩個分配
we can make a division between the four
cells that we saw earlier, but
分成了四個部分，對應到我們先前提到的四個細格
now we're visualizing it in another way.
也就是圖中的四塊顏色區域
If we look at the white bell shaped curve
白色的鐘型曲線之下的白色區域
就是正確拒絕(正陰性)
the white area reflects
the true negatives.
白色的鐘型曲線之下的白色區域
就是正確拒絕(正陰性)
There is no true effect to be observed and
we will find it a lot of the time.
這一塊表示不會觀察到真實效果，也是四塊區域最大的
We can also make a false positive.
紅色區域代表假警報的發生率
This is still part of
the distribution Often null, so
這塊也是虛無假設的一部分
the white curve slowly moves towards
this red are that you can see.
所以白色鐘型曲線向紅色區域緩慢傾斜
WIth the area of the false
positives pointing to it.
紅色區域面積代表結論是假警報發生機率
These are situations when we
observe an extreme result
代表虛無假設為真時，我們會觀察到極端結果的狀況
when the null hypothesis is true.
We're saying that there's something, but
we're actually making a type one error
這些狀況下宣稱有效果，就是犯了型一錯誤
Now let's switch our attention
to the light blue area.
接著來看淡藍色的區域
You can see that this falls on
the right side of the critical value.
這塊區域位於臨界值的右邊
So in this case, we are observing p
values that are smaller than 0.05 and
這代表如果觀察到的p值小於.05
並且宣稱有效果的結論是正確的情況
we are correctly saying
that there is an effect.
這代表如果觀察到的p值小於.05
並且宣稱有效果的結論是正確的情況
We're observing a significant result and
there is a true effect to be observed.
這個情況有顯著結果，而且確實觀察到真實效果
So the light blue area corresponds to
the true positives that we'll observe.
所以淡藍色區域對應於推論命中的結果
(正陽性)
Sometimes we'll conclude
that there is no effect
有時我們也會下結論說，沒有任何效果存在
when we're actually sampling from this
reality where this a true effect.
實際上資料取樣自有效果的分配
This is illustrated in the dark blue area.
這就是深藍色區域代表的情況
These are false negatives.
也就是未命中的推論(偽陰性)
The values we observe
are not extreme enough
這種情況獲得的資料不能獲得小於.05的p值
因此導致未命中的推論
to lead to a P value smaller than 0.05 So
these are false negatives.
這種情況獲得的資料不能獲得小於.05的p值
因此導致未命中的推論
Now the important question
when you're designing a study is,
現在回到最重要的問題
設計一個研究要如何設定結論的犯錯率？
which error rates should you aim for?
現在回到最重要的問題
設計一個研究要如何設定結論的犯錯率？
I already mentioned that the alpha
level and the beta that we often use
一開始曾提過心理學常設定
alpha是0.05,beta值是20%或者考驗力80%
is alpha 0.05 and the beta of 20% or
a statistical power of 80%.
一開始曾提過心理學常設定
alpha是0.05,beta值是20%或者考驗力80%
However statisticians themselves say
you should not use these benchmarks.
然而統計學家建議你不應該依賴這些參照標準
You should think for
yourself what the best choice is.
你應該自己想想，什麼是你的最佳選擇
Neyman himself talks about it in this way.
至少尼曼是這麼表示的
Is it more serious to convict
an innocent man, or to acquit a guilty?
他曾問「起訴一個無辜的人，與釋放一個罪犯，
那個較嚴重?」
if you're convicting an innocent man,
this person has done nothing.
如果你是檢察官，要起訴一個無辜的人，
但這人並沒做惡事
But you're saying this person has done
something, so this is Type 1 error.
你堅持這個人有罪，
就犯了型一錯誤
If you're acquitting a guilty man,
this person has done something wrong.
如果你決定釋放一個嫌犯，但這個人真做了惡事
But you're saying no crime has been
committed, so this is Type 2 error.
你堅持這個人無罪，
就犯了型二錯誤
Depending on your beliefs one of these two
types of errors might be more serious.
那種錯誤較嚴重，端看你的信念
In the case of medicine,
在醫學領域裡
we can see that you have to weigh this
two types of error very carefully.
兩種錯誤是以非常謹慎方式權衡
If you have Type 2 error and
you are saying, you are not sick.
如果你是醫生卻犯了型二錯誤
也就是你覺得患者並未生病
You don't need any treatment when
the person is actually sick.
不需要任何治療
但事實上患者是有病的
There might be very severe consequences
and this person might die.
這可能會導致患者死亡的嚴重後果
So there are more likely to
make an error whether you say,
因此寧可犯另一種的錯誤
you might have a specific sickness,
we're not completely sure.
也就是患者真有某種疾病，
只是還無法確切診斷
And then follow up research will
confirm this in more extensive tests.
然後持續研究，根據更廣泛的測試結果做結論
So Neyman himself says that determining
how the balance must be struck should be
所以尼曼表示，如何決定兩種錯誤的平衡點
應該要讓研究者自己決定
left to the investigator.
所以尼曼表示，如何決定兩種錯誤的平衡點
應該要讓研究者自己決定
So it's up to you to decide
what types of errors or
你(研究者)自已應該最清楚要避免那種錯誤
還有容許多大的犯錯率
what levels of errors you find acceptable.
你(研究者)自已應該最清楚要避免那種錯誤
還有容許多大的犯錯率
You don't really need to use these
defaults although they are very tempting.
雖然預設標準很方便
但你並非一定得採用
Cohen himself recommended
this 80% power threshold.
就像柯恩(Jacob Cohen)建議的80%統計考驗力
And when he did this, he explicitly hoped
that this recommendation would be ignored
他同時提到，若是研究者清楚知道自己要的考驗力
是多少，可忽略這項建議
whenever you as a researcher can
make better informed judgements.
他同時提到，若是研究者清楚知道自己要的考驗力
是多少，可忽略這項建議
At our department for example, we use
typically a 90% power if we're designing
以我任教的系來說，我們一般採用90%的統計考驗力
new studies where we hope that they will
lead to insights that we can publish.
來設計新研究，尤其是能導致可發表的新想法的研究
So, we have a 90% threshold because we try
to spend the tax money on research that
採用至少90%的考驗力是希望善用納稅人的錢做出
真正有意義的結果，就算沒發現顯著結果也ok
will give us informative results, even
when we don't find a significant result,
採用至少90%的考驗力是希望善用納稅人的錢做出
真正有意義的結果，就算沒發現顯著結果也ok
we want to be reasonably sure that
there's really nothing there,
我們講究即使沒有任何效果存在
也不要錯過任何蛛絲馬跡
that we didn't miss anything.
我們講究即使沒有任何效果存在
也不要錯過任何蛛絲馬跡
In the case where you're
examining very impactful things,
如果是檢視有重大意義的發現
where, if you find an effect,
you might have a real breakthrough.
特別是可能導致科學突破的某種效果
更要避免未命中的錯誤
So, missing out on a true
effect is very costly.
我們的考量是錯過發現真實效果是非常划不來的
You want to increase your power or reduce
your type two error as much as possible
必須儘可能增加統計考驗力，
或者降低型二錯誤
Most of the scientific discoveries that
lead to Nobel prizes are discovered by
大多數諾貝爾獎得主的重要發現，都是在35~40歲左右
people between 35 and 40 years of age. So
in my case I'm of course keeping my type
two error rate as small as possible.
所以我當然要儘量降低型二錯誤
Because at this moment when I do
a discovery and I miss out on something,
如果我的研究過程漏掉了某個重要發現
I could may be even be missing out
on a Nobel prize winning idea.
我可能會失去一個得諾貝爾獎的絕佳機會
So for me personally, I try to have
high power and low type two error rates.
就對我個人而言，最佳策略是提高統計考驗力
降低型二錯誤率
The type one error rate is
slightly less important.
型一錯誤就相對來說並沒有那麼重要
At the same time,
we see that people are very,
另一方面，常看到很研究者非常不喜歡
very hesitant to changeType 1 error rates.
或者抗拒調整型一錯誤率
You could even increase it.
其實你可以增加型一錯誤率
You could set your Type 1 error rates
to 10% and it's perfectly possible,
只要是你的研究條件允許
將型一錯誤率提高到10%也是可以接受的
If in your specific situation,
this is acceptable.
只要是你的研究條件允許
將型一錯誤率提高到10%也是可以接受的
But it's almost like Moses came
down from the Mount Sinai and
不過預設標準很像是摩西從西奈山帶出來
刻有十誡的石板
he had this tablet with
a ten commandments and
不過預設標準很像是摩西從西奈山帶出來
刻有十誡的石板
one of them was you will
always set your alpha to 0.05.
彷彿其中一誡是：把你的alpha 設在.05
People are very hesitant to change this
but if you really know what you're
人們非常不想去改變這個值。
但是若你真正知道你在做什麼
doing and you're making an informed
judgement, this is perfectly possible.
並且是深思熟慮後的決定，
改變alpha值是完全可行的
So it's very useful to think
about how you can control your
當你設計一項新研究時，
思考如何控制兩種錯誤率是非常有用的
error rates when you're
designing a new study.
當你設計一項新研究時，
思考如何控制兩種錯誤率是非常有用的
You want to minimize one or
both of these types of errors, so
你要降低一種或兩種犯錯率，
才能讓減少多次實驗被愚弄的機會
that in the long run, you won't make
a fool out of yourself too often.
你要降低一種或兩種犯錯率，
才能讓減少多次實驗被愚弄的機會
[Music]
課程結束